Sofiyullahi Jamiu

Software Developer



PROFILE

Mission-driven full-stack Software Developer with 5+ years of experience in web development, algorithms, software testing, and database management with the goal of offering top-quality service/experience by providing optimal software solutions and increasing business efficiency while delivering world-class results as smoothly as possible.



CONTACT

B7 4RF Compass, Bimingham, UK +44 740 325 4257 \times sofiyullahj@gmail.com https://orpcy.github.io/orpcy/



్ర్డ్ SKILLS & TOOLS

REACT **VS CODE JAVASCRIPT FIGMA** CHROME REMOTE DESKTOP **NODEJS**

HTML & CSS 700M

DATABASE MANAGEMENT **GITHUB**

WEB HOSTING

GIT/SOURCE CONTROL

NEXTJS REDUX



LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

YORUBA













Games

Music

Football Designing



EDUCATION

- Birmingham City University Birmingham, UK
 - · Master of User Experience Design
 - 2022 present
- University of Ilorin Ilorin, Nigeria
 - · Bachelor of Computer Science
 - 2014 2018



EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Emjay Solutions, Lagos, NIG, 2019-2022

- Migrated the company's web app from Pure VanillaJS to React.js for greater dynamism and a smoother UI.
- Tested applications for bugs/errors and developed software fixes.
- · Built a currency converter while utilising rest API to get live conversion rates using ReactJS.
- Discuss user needs and software solutions with organisations.
- Collaborated with software and hardware teams to bring products from conception to completion.

Frontend Developer(Remote)

UNPLUGDD, 2020-2021

- Developed a user-friendly and lightning-fast user interface.
- Helped backend engineers understand frontend components, their purpose, and how to integrate them best.
- I helped integrate a messaging system that lets people chat while watching live events to make it more entertaining and realistic.
- I worked with the team to build/integrate an automated 24/7 live support system that provides lists of complaints for users to choose from, making it easier and faster to reach out and reducing admin workload.

Freelance FullStack Developer

Various, 2018-2021

- Collaborated with developers from different parts of the world to assist them fix bugs and complete coding tasks/challenges.
- Mentored and provided guidance for new and aspiring web developers.
- · Participated in developer-oriented social events to network with peers from across the world, share insights on how to improve the user experience, and learn about the latest trends in Web development.





